Guide to the New York Metro Area Postal Union Oral History OH.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
New York Metro Area Postal Union Oral History
1976-1978
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Schechter, Dana
Cornell Universtiy
OH.003
2 Linear Feet in 2 flat boxes and 1 letter manuscript box
68 audiocassettes
This collection consists of oral history interviews of 15 retired officers or activists of the New York Metro Area Postal Union, as well as interview transcripts. The interviews cover the topics of postal service working conditions, the evolution of the Union and its leadership, the Local 10, the National Federation of Post Office Clerks, the organization of Postal Union of Manhattan – Bronx Clerks, National Postal Clerks Union, and the national postal strike of 1970. The collection also contains an extensive interview with Morris Biller, President of the union from 1959-80, when he became president of the national union.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Dana Schechter on behalf of Cornell University in circa 1989. The accession number associated with this gift is 1980.021.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by the interviewee's last name.
Historical Note
The New York Area Postal Union represents over 21,000 postal clerks, motor vehicle operators, maintenance, and mail handlers in New York and New Jersey. The local resulted from the 1958 secession of officers and members of Local 10, National Federation of Post Office Clerks, an organization dating back to 1901. The secessionists favored an industrial organization that would include all postal crafts.
Barbara Wertheimer, labor educator at Cornell NYSSILR's New York Labor Extension, conceived of an oral history project utilizing union retiree groups to document workers' contributions to New York City. The study of the New York Metro Postal Workers began in 1976 with a small grant under the direction of Dana Schecter. For two years, Schecter met with a group of retired postal workers, trained them in oral history techniques, and set them to the task of the interviewing. Schecter donated the tapes and transcripts to the Wagner Archives in 1980.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Related Materials
For more materials related to the New York Metro Area Postal Union, see:
New York Metro Area Postal Union Collection Records (WAG.103),
Josie McMillian's oral history interview in the New Yorkers at Work Oral History Collection (OH.001).
Scope and Contents
Barbara Wertheimer, labor educator at Cornell NYSSILR's New York Labor Extension, conceived of an oral history project utilizing union retiree groups to document workers' contributions to New York City. The study of the New York Metro Postal Workers began in 1976 with a small grant under the direction of Dana Schecter. For two years, Schecter met with a group of retired postal workers, trained them in oral history techniques, and set them to the task of the interviewing. Schecter donated the tapes and transcripts to the Wagner Archives in 1980.
This collection consists of oral history interviews of 15 retired officers or activists of the New York Metro Area Postal Union, as well as transcripts of each of the interviews. The interviews cover the topics of postal service working conditions, the evolution of the Union and its leadership, the Local 10, the National Federation of Post Office Clerks, the organization of Postal Union of Manhattan – Bronx Clerks, National Postal Clerks Union, and the national postal strike of 1970. The collection also contains an extensive interview with Morris Biller, President of the union from 1959-80, when he became president of the national union.
All interviews have master recordings (stored in Box 2) and user access copies (stored in Box 3). All interviews have paper transcripts with the exception of Leo Goodwin and Otto Gottlieb.
Labor unions -- Organizing -- New York (N.Y.); United States Postal Service |x Employees |x History.; Postal Strike -- United States -- 1970.; Strikes and lockouts |x Postal service.; Labor union leaders -- Portraits.; Labor union members |z United States.; Oral history.; Schechter, Dana; Cornell Universtiy
- Biller, Morris, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_001, 003_002, 003_003, 003_004, 003_005, 003_006, 003_007, 003_008, Box 3, Audiocassette 003_030, 003_031, 003_032, 003_033, 003_034, 003_035, 003_036, 003_037, Box 1, Folder 1, 2, 3)
  Scope and Contents
  Biller was President of New York Area Postal Union of the American Postal Workers, AFL-CIO, as well as Regional Coordinator for the Northeast Region of the American Workers' Postal Union.
- Epstein, Max, November, 1976 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_009, 003_010, Box 3, Audiocassette 003_038, 003_039, Box 1, Folder 4)
  Epstein discusses work experiences, McCarthyism and the Union in the 1930s.
- Goldberg, Bernard, November 26, 1976 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_011, Box 3, Audiocassette 003_040, 003_041, Box 1, Folder 5)
  Goldberg discusses finance insurance funds, substition work, and work inequities.
- Goodwin, Leo, November 30, 1976 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_012, Box 3, Audiocassette 003_042)
- Gottlieb, Otto, November 11, 1976 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_013, Box 3, Audiocassette 003_043)
- Kamish, Harry, December 9, 1976 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_014, Box 3, Audiocassette 003_044, Box 1, Folder 6)
  Kamish was a delegate addressing poor working conditions; he discusses the Summerfield suspension and the 1958 break from AFL-CIO.
- Kaye, Abraham, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_015, 003_016, Box 3, Audiocassette 003_047, 003_048, Box 1, Folder 7)
  Kaye was a supervisor who was with the postal service from 1913-1958.
- Mandell, Sidney, January 15, 1977 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_017, Box 3, Audiocassette 003_045, 003_046, Box 1, Folder 8)
  Mandell discusses being a woman on the job, GPO incoming mail, and general changes in the work environment.
- Resnick, Elsie, November 26, 1976 (Box 2, Audiocassette Unknown, Box 3, Audiocassette 003_047, Box 1, Folder 9)
  Elsie Resnick discusses sexism at work, working conditions, GPO incoming mail, Sick Aid, and the 1970 strike.
- Resnick, Robert, November 26, 1976 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_018, Box 3, Audiocassette 003_048, 003_049, 003_050, Box 1, Folder 10)
  Robert Resnick discusses supervisor negligence, GPO incoming mail, and the 1970 strike.
- Rosner, Milton, April 27, 1977 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_019, 003_020, 003_021, Box 3, Audiocassette 003_051, 003_052, 003_053, 003_054, 003_055, 003_056, 003_057, 003_058, Box 1, Folder 11)
  Rosner was Secretary-Treasurer of New York Metro Postal Workers; he discusses the credit union, politics and finances, and dangers of the job.
- Ryland, Arthur, November, 1976 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_022, 003_023, Box 3, Audiocassette 003_059, 003_060, Box 1, Folder 12)
  Ryland discusses racism, the lengthy fight to be allowed to sit on the job, case stories, and the 1969 Contsitution Convention.
- Salk, Charles, June 28, 1976 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_024, Box 3, Audiocassette 003_061, 003_062, Box 1, Folder 13)
  Salk discusses early labor conditions, his rise to leadership, and Dave Edelson.
- Seligman, Philip, June 29, 1976 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_025, Box 3, Audiocassette 003_063, 003_064, Box 1, Folder 14)
  This group interview discusses the break from AFL-CIO and the fight to enforce exams for managers, among other topics.
- Group Interview: Rosner, Ryland, Salk, 1977 (Box 2, Audiocassette 003_026, 003_027, 003_028, 003_029, Box 3, Audiocassette 003_065, 003_066, 003_067, 003_068, Box 1, Folder 15, 16)